Curriculum Vitae

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Satish Abhayraj Yadav
Mobile: (+91) 9004902606
E-mail: satishy051@gmail.com

Location: Dombivali East

SUMMARY

A highly resourceful, innovative, and competent PHP developer and Technical support executive with extensive experience in the layout, design and coding of websites specifically in PHP format.

Possessing considerable knowledge of the development of web applications and scripts using PHP programming language and MySQL Server databases.

Experienced in developing applications and giving application support to a wide range of clients.

EDUCATION HISTORY

August 2011 University of Mumbai,

Bachelor Of Science (I.T)

March 2008 Maharashtra Board,

H.S.C

March 2006 Maharashtra Board,

S.S.C

WORK EXPERIENCE

11 Months Chenoa Information Services Pvt Ltd (February 2022 – Present)

[Application Support Engineer L2]

- Extensive Application Support.
- Ticketing Tools.
- Server health checkups.
- App health checkup.
- Data management
- Escalation ticket resolution
- Client co-ordination on daily basis

4.5 Years

Digi Interface, Malad West (December, 2020 – December 2021)

Digi Interface, Malad West (February, 2015 – June 2018)

[Sr. PHP Developer, Technical Support]

- Backend portal development.
- Web Services.
- API creation and integration
- Payment Gateways.
- Custom CMS development.
- Extensive Application Support.

SKILLS

Technical Details:

Technologies Used: PHP,Jquery,Javascript,Rest,HTML,CSS

System Hardware: Backups and restore, Installation, Configuration, Maintenance

Framework: Codeigniter

Web Server: Apache

Remote Tool: Any Desk

Computer Proficiency: Window OS, Windows Server and M S Office

Database: MySQL

Application: WAMP

FTP Client: Winscp, Filezilla

Development Tools: NetBeans, Notepad ++

DUTIES

- Developing web sites using MySQL, PHP & other programming tools.
- Integration of payment gateways like CCavenue, Agreepay, etc
- Third party API integration.

- Building PHP websites using PHP based frameworks.
- Creation of APIs.
- SQL Installation, Database creation, Backup and restoration, Updating database, Table creation, Selecting and Retrieving of data from Database
- Monitored and tuned database resources and activities for SQL Server databases.
- Created and optimized SQL queries.
- Provided extensive Application Support.
- Provided HelpDesk and Technical Support.
- Planning and conducting cross-browser usability testing. Testing and validating work produced as part of the development process.
- Back end development and maintenance of websites using PHP and MySQL.
- Developing compatible User Interface functionality using jQuery & other libraries.

PROJECTS

Efee.

URL - https://efee.in Technology Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- A fees payment portal where the user can make fees payment of respective students.
- Backend portal wherein the admin can update fees structure, view student stats, etc.
- Payment gateway integration .
- Various other modules like institute and payment made to keep track for fees and oter data.
- Backend developed to maintain content of site.
- Creation and management of SQL Server database.
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.

Crapcandy.

URL - https://crapcandy.com Technology Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- A social media site wherein the user can login and create blogs related to audio video or text
- Custom like comment and chat feature embedded into the site.
- Third party integration of youtube, soundcloud and other audio video sites.
- Custom audio player creation.
- Backend developed to maintain content of site.
- Integration of Third party login APIs like google and facebook
- Creation and management of SQL Server database.
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.

Vishva Times.

URL - http://www.vishvatimes.com
Technology Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL
Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- A news portal where the admin can post news based on different categories like sports, entertainment, astrology, etc.
- Backend developed to maintain content of site.
- Integration of Third party APIs
- Creation and management of SQL Server database .
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.

Shree Udyan Ganesh

URL - http://shreeudyanganesh.com
Technologies Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL
Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- The official website of Shree Udyan Ganesh Mandir.
- Panel made for keeping track of donations and other data.
- Payment Gateway Integrated for donations.
- Support for payment related queries.
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases
- Provide report to client on various levels.
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.

Six Of Us Designs.

URL - http://www.sixofusdesign.com Technology Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- A custom CMS made for a designing studio.
- Creation of admin panel to manage content for site.
- Resolving day-to-day queries of client
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.
- Maintaining database and modifications in application

Greater Grace fellowship

URL - http://ggfmumbai.org
Technologies Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL
Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- Greater Grace Fellowship is a non-denominational evangelical church.
- CMS maintained for controlling the messages, notes, audio and other content of the site.
- Resolving day-to-day queries of client
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases

- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.
- Maintaining database and modifications in application

BNB Group

URL - http://bnbgroupe.com Technologies Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- Panel made for adding products, categories and other contents for the site.
- Backend developed to maintain content of site.
- Resolving day-to-day queries of client
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.

Inavit Modutech

URL - http://inavitmodutech.com
Technologies Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL
Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- An Indian origin company dealing in Modular kitchen, Kitchen appliances and machine made furniture.
- Portal created for maintaining their inventory and other content displayed on the site.
- Resolving day-to-day gueries of client
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.

VertVista

URL - http://vertvista.com
Technologies Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL
Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- VertVista Eco Solutions Pvt Ltd. is a designer landscape engineering firm specializing in Green Walls, Terrace Gardens and Urban Landscaping solutions.
- VertVista is an authorized representative of the renowned Singapore based landscaping company, Elmich Pte. Ltd., for India.
- Creation of a backend panel for adding products, categories and other contents to be displayed on the site .
- Resolving day-to-day queries of client
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.
- Maintaining database and modifications in application

Wiltex Limited

URL - http://wiltexlimited.com Technologies Used - PHP (Codeigniter) ,MySQL Applications Used - Netbeans , Navigat , Winscp

- Wiltex Limited, a dynamic trading house specialises in a wide variety of industrial requirements like machineries, electrical parts & accessories, automobiles, etc.
- Creation of a backend panel for adding and updating products , categories and other content to be displayed on the site.
- Integration of backend data into the site.
- Resolving day-to-day queries of client
- Creation and management of SQL Server databases
- Provide solutions through remote or telephonic support.
- Maintaining database and modifications in application

I HEREBY DECLARE THAT ALL INFORMATION STATED ABOVE IS TRUE TO THE BEST OF MY KNOWLEDGE AND BELIEF.

Place: Mumbai Satish Yadav